翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
I like to call this little puzzle here the mystery of the walrus.
我喜欢把这个小谜题叫做“海象之谜”
So we now know the answer to the mystery of the walrus, that is why the walrus behaves one way and integers behave another.
我们已经知道了海象之谜的答案，海象和整型的行为方式不同
But we want to understand really why.
我们要了解真正的原因
And so to get to that, I'm going to explain a little bit about how computers work under the hood.
为此，我要稍微解释一下计算机底层工作原理
Now, this is a little bit of a fib, be warned.
请注意，我要讲的不是很严谨
And in the book, I lay out a little more of an honest story.
书中描述得更真实
But for our purposes, this is basically true.
但目前对于我们而言，这基本是正确的
So anything you want to store on a computer is stored in so-called memory.
你想放到计算机中的任何东西都存储在所谓的内存中
And that memory, whatever it is-- I mean, is it an arrangement of atoms?
这个内存不用管它是什么，它是原子的排列？
Is it like crystals that have been imbued with the power of the gods?
或者是充斥着神力的水晶？
Who knows?
谁知道呢？
But whatever it is, ultimately that memory is--
但不管它是什么，基本上内存是
all information is encoded as a sequence of 1's and 0's.
编码为1和0的信息序列
So some examples.
举几个例子
In a computer, the number 72 is usually stored as 01001000.
在计算机中，数字72通常存储为01001000
Or as another example, the number 205.75 is often stored as 01000011, et cetera, with 32 more 0's up here.
数字205.75通常存储为01000011...还有32个0
The letter H, for example, it's often stored as 01001000.
例如字母 H 通常存储为01001000
And you'll notice that's actually the same as the number 72, they have the same encoding.
这实际上和数字72是一样的，它们有相同的编码
And the computer knows how to interpret those bits based on the particular context.
计算机知道如何基于特定的上下文来解释这些比特
And as a last example, the value "true" is often stored as a bunch of 0's followed by 1.
最后一个例子，“true”通常存储为一串0后跟一个1
Now, it's not always the case that "true" is always stored this way or 72 is always stored this way.
“true”或者72并不总是以上述方式存储
But these are the most typical representations.
但基本是这样
And so if you're really curious about this stuff,
如果你真的对这些东西很好奇
this class isn't really going to dig deep into representations.
这节课不会深入介绍
But suffice it to say that given anything that you can name,
能说出你命名的东西就行了
you can certainly come up with some sequence of 1's and 0's and say it refers to that thing.
你可以想出一些1和0的序列，然后说它指的是某个东西
So each Java type--
每种Java类型...
so when you have a Java variable,
当你有一个 Java 变量时
even though the letter H and the number 72 have separate representations,
即使字母 H 和数字72具有不同的表示
the type tells the Java interpreter how to interpret it.
类型系统告诉 Java 解释器如何解释它
So if I have a variable that's of type character,
假设我有一个字符类型的变量
then when it sees the sequence of bits,
然后观察它的比特序列
it's going to be thinking about the letter H.
会想到字母 H
But if I have an integer variable,
但是假设我有一个整型变量
it will know to treat it as the number 72.
它将被其视为数字72
So it turns out that in Java, there's eight primitive types.
在 Java 中有8种基本类型
There's byte, short, int, long, float, double, boolean, and char.
byte、short、int、long、float、double、boolean 和 char
And we're not going to spend a ton of time talking about each of these types.
我们不会花太多时间一一讨论
But be aware these are the eight primitive types.
但请注意这8种基本类型
And so again, as I alluded, we're not going to say why is 205.75 equal to this sequence of bits.
再说一次，我们不会讲为什么205.75等于这个比特序列
That's actually a class that follows this one called 61C.
这实际上在后面 61C 的课程中会讲到
But if you're curious, you can go reading.
但是如果你好奇，可以去看看书
And the book give some links if you want to get ahead of the game.
书会给你一些链接，让你抢占先机
But in this course, all I really care about right now,
但在这门课上，我现在真正关心的是
I want to understand why does the mystery of the walrus resolve in the way it does?
为什么海象之谜会以这种方式解开？
And this is a piece of information that I think is really useful to us in understanding that.
这条信息对我们理解很有用
So what we're going to do is
所以我们要做的是
let's use this simple model of declaring a variable and combine that with our knowledge of bits
将声明变量的简单模型和比特知识相结合
to really reinforce the fundamentals we'll need for the mystery of the walrus.
来加强了解海象之谜的基础
So here's some code.
这里有一些代码
I'm going to run it in a moment.
一会运行它
So when you declare a variable of a certain type in Java,
当你在 Java 中声明某个类型的变量时
say int x or double y, what happens is your computer's going to set aside exactly enough bits to hold a thing of that type.
比方说 int x 或 double y，计算机会留出足够的位数来容纳这种类型的东西
It's got some billions of bits that it can use.
它有数十亿比特可以使用
And it's going to say, these bits are going to get to be int x.
它会安排：“这些位将会是 int x”
These are going to get to be double y.
“这些会变成 double y”
So an int, as it turns out, is always 32 bits.
int 始终是32位
Even if you only are storing a small number,
即使只存储了一小部分数据
it still gives you 32 bits.
计算机仍然提供32位
Or if you declare a double, you get 64 bits.
或者声明为双精度会得到64位
That's just how it is.
就是这样
And so Java, what it will then do is it's going to create some kind of table that says,
Java 会创建一张表，上面写着
OK, anytime I see the symbol x, that means I'm referring to this piece of information.
“每当我看到符号 x，就意味着指的是这条信息”
And Java does not write anything in particular into those boxes.
而且 Java 不会向分配好的盒子中写入任何内容
So it's got this huge sequence of bits.
它有一个巨大的比特序列
It says, these get to be x.
上面写着，这些应该是 x
And it just records, OK, from now on when I see x, I mean this memory.
它只记录，“从现在开始当我看到 x 时，指的是这块内存区”
And so if I look at this visually,
从视觉上看
after running this int x, I get a block of 32 bits.
运行 int x 后，我得到一个32位的区域
And after running double y, I get this box of 64 bits.
运行 double y 后，我得到了这个64位的盒子
Now, note that I haven't put anything in here.
注意此时我没有在这里放任何东西
Now, there is something in there.
其实里面本身存在一些东西
I mean, because memory is just some physical object out there in the world, the memory will contain some sequence of 0's and 1's.
内存会包含一些0和1的序列，因为它是自然界的物理对象
But Java does not let you actually access the information that's laying around.
但是 Java 实际上并不允许你访问
It's sort of like if you pick up a piece of paper off your desk because you needed to scribble a quick note,
这有点像你需要草草写个便条，所以从桌子上拿起一张纸
there may already be something on there.
纸上可能已经有东西了
But you usually don't care about it, right,
但你通常并不在意
because you just want to write down a phone number someone's telling you or whatever.
因为你只想写下别人告诉你的电话号码
So there might already be something there,
所以内存中可能已经有东西了
but Java will not let you see what's already there.
但是 Java 不会让你看到已经存在的内容
There's just no way to see that information.
就是没办法看到这些信息
So in this case, what I'm saying is that Java doesn't let you access a variable that's uninitialized.
Java 不允许访问未初始化的变量
So if I tried to print x or y at this point, it would say no, not allowed.
所以这时尝试打印 x 或 y，都不会被允许
So that's declaration.
这就是声明
So now let's talk a little bit about assignment.
再来谈谈赋值
So whenever I say x equals some big number like this,
每当我说 x 等于一个像这样的大数字时
what Java will do is then fill it with all the bits that correspond to this number.
Java 就会用与该数字相对应的所有位来填充它
And it turns out that the 32 bits that correspond to this negative number here is this sequence of bits.
与这个负数相对应的32位就是这个比特序列
And when I say y equals this right here, well,
当执行 y 等于这里的时候
what it will do is fill that with the 64 bits that represent this particular number.
代表这个数字的64位比特序列填充它
And of course, there's some code under the hood that knows exactly how all this works.
底层代码确切地知道这一切是如何工作的
There is a whole stack of interesting abstractions that go down to the hardware level.
有一大堆深入到硬件级别的有趣的抽象
And that's really 61C's purview, to say just how these bits happen.
61C 会说明这些比特是如何工作的
But for our purposes to understand the mystery of the walrus, this is what you should know.
但这里只是为了理解海象之谜
We get two boxes.
我们有两个盒子
Then they get filled up with bits.
它们被比特填满
So what?
然后呢？
Well, we're getting there.
马上就知道了
But before we get deeper, I want to introduce a little simpler notation.
但在深入之前，我想介绍一个更简单的符号
So whenever you look at this, this is probably if nothing else a little intimidating, right?
这个可能是有点吓人对吧？
This is just some giant long sequence of bits.
一个超长的比特序列
So this box notation that I have introduced,
所以我要介绍盒子符号
I'm now going to make it even simpler and call it simplified box notation.
用以简化表示它，我称之为简化盒子表示法
And in this notation, what we're going to do is instead of writing out the memory box contents in binary,
在这个表示法中，不使用二进制表示盒子的内容
because I can't read that, you can't read that, we're just going to write out the value in human-readable symbols.
因为难以阅读，我们要把值写成人类易读的符号
So when I say x equals this, I will just fill the box.
所以当我说 x 等于这个的时候，这样填满盒子
That's going to be our notation.
这是我们的记号
And it happens to be consistent with the Java visualizer we use in this class.
这恰好与 Java visualizer 中一致
So now that we know about bits, I'm now really to tell you why the mystery of the walrus resolves the way it does.
我们已经了解了比特，现在我要告诉你海象之谜究竟怎样解开
And that's because it follows what I'm going to call the golden rule of equals.
它遵循的是我称之为等号的黄金法则
So given two variables, y and x, when I say y equals x,
假设有两个变量 y 和 x，当 y = x 时
I'm just taking all the bits in x and copying them into y.
只是把 x 中的所有位复制到 y 中
So let's look at this in action, now keeping in mind our picture of simplified box notation.
让我们来看一下实际操作，记住我们的简化盒子表示法
So when I say int x equals 5, I get a box that contains the number 5.
执行 int x = 5 时，得到一个包含数字5的盒子
And when I do int y, I get a box-- not pictured here,
执行 int y 时，得到一个盒子，但没有图形
because the visualizer chooses not to do so.
因为可视化工具选择不生成图形
And so when I say y equals x, it's just going to copy those bits that are in x and the y.
当执行 y = x 时，它只会将 x 中的位复制到 y
So there they go.
就像这样
They're in the box.
它们在盒子里
And now if I say x equals 2,
现在执行 x = 2
remember what the golden rule of equals does is it says it takes these bits and puts them in this box.
依据等号的黄金法则，它会把这些位放进这个盒子里
So what are these bits?
这些位是什么呢？
It's the number 2.
是数字2
And it puts them in which box?
它们会被放在哪个盒子里？
This box.
这个盒子
So there's no change to y, because that's not what the golden rule of equals says.
所以 y 没有变化，因为等号的黄金法则不是这样
It says, take this box and fill it with bits.
将这个盒子装满比特
Not this box. There's two distinct boxes.
不是这个盒子，这两个盒子截然不同
Fill this one up.
把这个装满
And that's the answer to why integers behave the way they do.
这就是整型行为方式的答案
So the natural follow-up question is, well, what about walruses?
那么接下来的问题，海象呢？
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
And we'll get there in a moment.
马上揭晓